[
    {
        "question": "Which US President signed an executive order making English the official language of the U.S.?",
        "options": [
            "Bill Clinton",
            "Barack Obama",
            "Donald Trump",
            "Joe Biden"
        ],
        "answer": "Donald Trump"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did President Trump's executive order on the official language of the U.S. rescind?",
        "options": [
            "A policy requiring English to be the only language used by federal agencies.",
            "A 2000 policy by Bill Clinton that required language assistance for non-English speakers.",
            "A law establishing bilingual education in public schools.",
            "The constitutional right to use languages other than English."
        ],
        "answer": "A 2000 policy by Bill Clinton that required language assistance for non-English speakers."
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was elected as the new Prime Minister of Tonga, securing 16 votes in parliament, following the resignation of Siaosi Sovaleni?",
        "options": [
            "Viliami Latu",
            "Siaosi Sovaleni",
            "Aisake Valu Eke",
            "Akilisi Pohiva",
            "Rahsail Bino"
        ],
        "answer": "Aisake Valu Eke"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the recent development regarding the slogan 'Joy Bangla' in Bangladesh?",
        "options": [
            "It has been declared the national anthem of Bangladesh.",
            "It has been adopted as the official motto of the central bank of Bangladesh.",
            "It is being promoted as a cultural phrase by the new government, not a national anthem.",
            "The Supreme Court has stayed the High Court's decision to make it the national slogan.",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is the theme country at the 30th Kolkata International Film Festival (KIFF) 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Germany",
            "Japan",
            "France",
            "Italy",
            "Pakistan"
        ],
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did the inaugural India-Cambodia Joint Table Top Exercise CINBAX take place in December 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Phnom Penh, Cambodia",
            "Umroi, Meghalaya",
            "Pune, Maharashtra",
            "Siem Reap, Cambodia",
            "New Delhi, India"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "With which country is India conducting the 4th edition of the joint military exercise HARIMAU SHAKTI in December 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Indonesia",
            "Malaysia",
            "Thailand",
            "Vietnam",
            "Myanmar"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country unveiled the new stealth fighter jet, the J-36, which has raised alarms globally, particularly in the Indo-Pacific region?",
        "options": [
            "Russia",
            "China",
            "United States",
            "India",
            "Japan"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which traditional Bosnian love song, dating back to the 16th century and blending South Slavic oral poetry with Ottoman musical influences, was recently added to UNESCO's Representative List of the Intangible Cultural Heritage of Humanity?",
        "options": [
            "Sevdalinka",
            "Klapa",
            "Ojkanje",
            "Ganga",
            "Akanji"
        ],
        "answer": "Sevdalinka"
    },
    {
        "question": "The European Free Trade Association (EFTA) comprise of which of the following group of nations?",
        "options": [
            "Finland, Norway, Sweden, Denmark",
            "Germany, Belgium, France, Spain",
            "Switzerland, Norway, Sweden, Finland",
            "Iceland, Liechtenstein, Norway and Switzerland",
            "France, Spain, Germany, Belgium"
        ],
        "answer": "Iceland, Liechtenstein, Norway and Switzerland"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which NASA mission recently made a historic close approach to the Sun at a distance of 6.1 million kilometers?",
        "options": [
            "Voyager 1",
            "Parker Solar Probe",
            "Juno",
            "Axiom 4",
            "Plutus 3"
        ],
        "answer": "Parker Solar Probe"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country declared the end of the Marburg virus outbreak after no new cases were reported in a 42-day observation period?",
        "options": [
            "Uganda",
            "Rwanda",
            "Kenya",
            "Tanzania",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which group, known for leading the Syrian rebels, declared Damascus 'liberated' and announced the end of Bashar al-Assad's government...?",
        "options": [
            "Free Syrian Army",
            "Hayat Tahrir al-Sham",
            "Islamic State",
            "Al-Qaeda",
            "Hezbollah"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the 2024 Asian Youth and Junior Weightlifting Championships being held?",
        "options": [
            "Tokyo, Japan",
            "Doha, Qatar",
            "New Delhi, India",
            "Bangkok, Thailand",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which countries will jointly host the 2030 FIFA World Cup?",
        "options": [
            "Spain, Portugal, and Morocco",
            "Saudi Arabia, Morocco, and Argentina",
            "Spain, France, and Italy",
            "Portugal, Argentina, and Brazil",
            "Saudi Arabia, Portugal, and Morocco"
        ],
        "answer": "Spain, Portugal, and Morocco"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is India\u2019s total external debt in 2023, as per the World Bank International Debt Report?",
        "options": [
            "$610.67 billion",
            "$635.84 billion",
            "$646.79 billion",
            "$655.74 billion",
            "$675.95 billion"
        ],
        "answer": "$646.79 billion"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which word was named Oxford Word of the Year 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Screen Fatigue",
            "Digital Burnout",
            "Information Overload",
            "Brain Rot",
            "Rizz"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the Gympie-Gympie plant, the World's Most Toxic Plant, scientifically known as Dendrocnide moroides, native to?",
        "options": [
            "Africa",
            "South America",
            "Australia",
            "Southeast Asia",
            "North America"
        ],
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is set to allow visa-free entry for Indian tourists starting March 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Japan",
            "Russia",
            "Canada",
            "Germany",
            "China"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bird was officially declared the national bird of the United States, symbolizing American strength and freedom since 1782?",
        "options": [
            "Peregrine Falcon",
            "Golden Eagle",
            "American Robin",
            "Bald Eagle",
            "White Pigeon"
        ],
        "answer": "Bald Eagle"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following organization has adopted 02 December as the International Day for the Abolition of Slavery?",
        "options": [
            "World Labour Organization",
            "United Nations General Assembly",
            "World Bank",
            "International Red Cross Society",
            "None of the Above"
        ],
        "answer": "United Nations General Assembly"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who became the shortest-serving Prime Minister in the history of the French Fifth Republic after being defeated in a confidence vote in December 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Emmanuel Macron",
            "Michel Barnier",
            "Marine Le Pen",
            "Jean-Luc M\u00e9lenchon",
            "None of the Above"
        ],
        "answer": "Michel Barnier"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the recent United Nations report on drylands, what percentage of Earth's land has become drier over the last 30 years?",
        "options": [
            "45%",
            "55%",
            "77%",
            "88%",
            "99%"
        ],
        "answer": "77%"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Nicaragua, where India and Nicaragua recently signed an MoU for Quick Impact Projects?",
        "options": [
            "Managua",
            "San Salvador",
            "Tegucigalpa",
            "Bogot\u00e1",
            "Harare"
        ],
        "answer": "Managua"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the Maldives' Minister of Foreign Affairs who made an official visit to India from 2nd January to 4th January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Mohamed Nasheed",
            "Abdulla Shahid",
            "Abdulla Khaleel",
            "Ibrahim Solih",
            "Ahmed Naseem"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "World Braille Day is celebrated to mark the birthday of Louis Braille, the inventor of Braille system for the blind, on?",
        "options": [
            "January 4th",
            "February 4th",
            "January 5th",
            "February 5th",
            "January 10th"
        ],
        "answer": "January 4th"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country introduced a 1% tourist tax on lodging costs to support tourism infrastructure starting January 1, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "France",
            "Russia",
            "Italy",
            "Germany",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Latin-American country declared a 60-day state of emergency in seven provinces due to rising crime and organized armed groups in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Colombia",
            "Peru",
            "Venezuela",
            "Ecuador",
            "Uruguay"
        ],
        "answer": "Ecuador"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which countries began assuming responsibilities as non-permanent members of the United Nations Security Council for two-year term?",
        "options": [
            "Denmark, Japan, Pakistan, Greece, and Somalia",
            "Japan, Germany, India, Greece, and Panama",
            "Denmark, Pakistan, Greece, India, and Panama",
            "Denmark, Greece, Pakistan, Panama, and Somalia",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the 21st Third Eye Asian Film Festival held, which screened 61 films from across Asia?",
        "options": [
            "Mumbai",
            "Delhi",
            "Bengaluru",
            "Kolkata",
            "Noida"
        ],
        "answer": "Mumbai"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has been confirmed as the host for the 2034 FIFA World Cup?",
        "options": [
            "Morocco",
            "Portugal",
            "Saudi Arabia",
            "Qatar",
            "Senegal"
        ],
        "answer": "Saudi Arabia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is set to launch a free mRNA cancer vaccine in 2025?",
        "options": [
            "United States",
            "Russia",
            "Germany",
            "China",
            "UK"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which mechanism was established between India and Kuwait in December, 2024 to enhance bilateral cooperation?",
        "options": [
            "Joint Trade Commission",
            "Joint Commission for Cooperation",
            "Strategic Partnership Council",
            "Economic Collaboration Council",
            "None of the Above"
        ],
        "answer": "Joint Commission for Cooperation"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is Mayotte, which was severely impacted by Cyclone Chido?",
        "options": [
            "Indian Ocean, a French overseas department",
            "Pacific Ocean, an autonomous region of France",
            "Atlantic Ocean, a territory of Spain",
            "Arabian Sea, an island nation",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Indian Ocean, a French overseas department"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has become Africa's largest investor, with Emirati companies announcing $110 billion in projects between 2019 and 2023, including $72 billion in renewable energy?",
        "options": [
            "Qatar",
            "United States",
            "United Arab Emirates",
            "China",
            "Bahrain"
        ],
        "answer": "United Arab Emirates"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which military exercise is being held in Nepal with participation from India and Nepal armies in December 2024-January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Exercise SHAKTI",
            "Exercise MAITREE",
            "Exercise SURYA KIRAN",
            "Exercise SAMPREETI",
            "Exercise TARANG"
        ],
        "answer": "Exercise SURYA KIRAN"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country's astronauts broke NASA's spacewalk record by completing a 9-hour EVA outside the Tiangong space station?",
        "options": [
            "China",
            "USA",
            "Japan",
            "Russia",
            "India"
        ],
        "answer": "China"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country recently unveiled the CR450 prototype, the world's fastest high-speed train?",
        "options": [
            "Japan",
            "Germany",
            "China",
            "South Korea",
            "Italy"
        ],
        "answer": "China"
    },
    {
        "question": "SLINEX (Sri Lanka-India Exercise) was recently conducted in December 2024. When was it first held?",
        "options": [
            "2002",
            "2005",
            "2012",
            "2015",
            "2019"
        ],
        "answer": "2005"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company did Elon Musk\u2019s X partner with to begin its financial services push?",
        "options": [
            "Paytm",
            "Apple Pay",
            "Visa",
            "Mastercard",
            "Google Pay"
        ],
        "answer": "Visa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has banned multiple entry visas for 14 nations, including India?",
        "options": [
            "USA",
            "Saudi Arabia",
            "Russia",
            "China",
            "United Kingdom"
        ],
        "answer": "Saudi Arabia"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many peacekeepers and Nobel Laureates attended Dubai\u2019s Global Justice Summit?",
        "options": [
            "5,000",
            "2,000",
            "3,000",
            "2,800",
            "1,500"
        ],
        "answer": "2,800"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which UN organization did Donald Trump withdraw the US from?",
        "options": [
            "UNESCO",
            "UNHRC",
            "UNFPA",
            "WHO",
            "UNDP"
        ],
        "answer": "UNHRC"
    },
    {
        "question": "When did the President of the 79th Session of the UN General Assembly, H.E. Mr. Philemon Yang, visit India?",
        "options": [
            "1\u20133 February 2025",
            "4\u20137 February 2025",
            "5\u20139 February 2025",
            "10\u201313 February 2025",
            "15\u201317 February 2025"
        ],
        "answer": "4\u20137 February 2025"
    },
    {
        "question": "What exercise was conducted by the Indian Army and IAF in the Eastern Theater?",
        "options": [
            "Thunderbolt",
            "Tornado Strike",
            "Winged Raider",
            "Vajra Shakti",
            "Iron Fist"
        ],
        "answer": "Winged Raider"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country, along with India, has completed two years of the Economic Cooperation and Trade Agreement (ECTA), aiming to reach AUD 100 billion in trade by 2030?",
        "options": [
            "United States",
            "United Kingdom",
            "Canada",
            "Australia",
            "Japan"
        ],
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who co-chaired the Artificial Intelligence (AI) Action Summit held in France?",
        "options": [
            "India and UK",
            "India and USA",
            "India and France",
            "India and Germany",
            "India and China"
        ],
        "answer": "India and France"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country launched 'Operation Devil Hunt' after former minister's supporters resisted 'vandalism'?",
        "options": [
            "India",
            "Bangladesh",
            "Pakistan",
            "Sri Lanka",
            "Nepal"
        ],
        "answer": "Bangladesh"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where will the 72nd edition of the Miss World pageant be held?",
        "options": [
            "Mumbai",
            "Hyderabad, Telangana",
            "New Delhi",
            "Kolkata",
            "Bangalore"
        ],
        "answer": "Hyderabad, Telangana"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the theme of the 9th edition of the Asia Economic Dialogue (AED) 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Globalization in the 21st Century",
            "Economic Resilience and Resurgence in an Era of Fragmentation",
            "Strengthening Global Trade Agreements",
            "Overcoming Geopolitical Challenges",
            "The Rise of Emerging Markets"
        ],
        "answer": "Economic Resilience and Resurgence in an Era of Fragmentation"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the international art exhibition \"Topographies of Tents, Terracotta, and Time\" being held?",
        "options": [
            "Mumbai",
            "Kolkata",
            "Hyderabad",
            "Pune",
            "Bengaluru"
        ],
        "answer": "Hyderabad"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which new bat coronavirus was discovered by researchers in China?",
        "options": [
            "SARS-CoV-2",
            "HKU5-CoV-2",
            "MERS-CoV",
            "H1N1",
            "Zika Virus"
        ],
        "answer": "HKU5-CoV-2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is India enhancing its media ties with ahead of WAVES 2025?",
        "options": [
            "United States",
            "United Kingdom",
            "Saudi Arabia",
            "Japan",
            "Russia"
        ],
        "answer": "Saudi Arabia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main objective of the training program between India\u2019s NCGG and Sri Lanka\u2019s SLIDA?",
        "options": [
            "Enhance trade relations",
            "Train 1,500 civil officers",
            "Promote tourism",
            "Train Indian officers",
            "Develop defense sector"
        ],
        "answer": "Train 1,500 civil officers"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did the first Conference for Women Peacekeepers, themed \"Women in Peacekeeping: A Global South Perspective,\" take place?",
        "options": [
            "Mumbai",
            "New Delhi",
            "Chennai",
            "Kolkata",
            "Bangalore"
        ],
        "answer": "New Delhi"
    },
    {
        "question": "What day has Bangladesh officially declared as Military Martyrdom Day?",
        "options": [
            "February 26",
            "February 25",
            "March 1",
            "January 15",
            "December 16"
        ],
        "answer": "February 25"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which region has been projected by the WHO to witness an 85% increase in cancer cases and deaths by 2050?",
        "options": [
            "Africa",
            "Europe",
            "North America",
            "South-East Asia",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where will India open a new Consulate during PM Modi's visit to France in February 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Nice",
            "Marseille",
            "Lyon",
            "Toulouse",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the world's largest iceberg that is set to strike South Georgia Island?",
        "options": [
            "Iceberg B15",
            "Iceberg A23a",
            "Iceberg C19",
            "Iceberg D16",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where in West Asia is the Medlab Middle East 2025 exhibition being held?",
        "options": [
            "Riyadh, Saudi Arabia",
            "Dubai, UAE",
            "Doha, Qatar",
            "Khartoum, Sudan",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has decided to end aid programs for Bangladesh, Albania, and Zambia due to a reduced foreign aid budget?",
        "options": [
            "Germany",
            "Switzerland",
            "France",
            "Sweden",
            "Japan"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which South-East Asian country declared a food security emergency to curb soaring rice prices in 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Vietnam",
            "Thailand",
            "Indonesia",
            "Philippines",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the theme of World Wetlands Day 2025 celebrated at Parvati Arga Ramsar Site in Gonda, Uttar Pradesh?",
        "options": [
            "Wetlands and Water",
            "Protecting Wetlands for our Common Future",
            "Wetlands and Biodiversity",
            "Sustainable Wetlands for a Better Tomorrow",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much did India contribute to the United Nations Regular Budget for the year 2025?",
        "options": [
            "$25.34 million",
            "$37.64 million",
            "$40.12 million",
            "$50.91 million",
            "$66.91 million"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country became the first in Africa to eliminate onchocerciasis (river blindness) as a public health problem?",
        "options": [
            "Niger",
            "Kenya",
            "South Africa",
            "Democratic Republic of Congo",
            "Eritrea"
        ],
        "answer": "Niger"
    },
    {
        "question": "Former world number one and two-time Grand Slam winner Simona Halep announced her retirement from professional tennis in February 2025. Which country does she hail from?",
        "options": [
            "Albania",
            "Croatia",
            "Romania",
            "Germany",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Romania"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which project led to the creation of a new map of the Arctic Ocean, revealing an area twice the size of France and six times the size of England?",
        "options": [
            "Ocean Discovery 2050",
            "Seabed 2030",
            "Arctic Exploration Initiative",
            "Deep Sea Mapping Project",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country announced a 25% retaliatory tariff on American imports in response to U.S. trade policies?",
        "options": [
            "China",
            "Canada",
            "Mexico",
            "Germany",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country's mission successfully demonstrated artificial photosynthesis in space?",
        "options": [
            "United States - Artemis",
            "Russia - Soyuz MS",
            "China - Shenzhou-19",
            "India - Gaganyaan",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country will host the BRICS Youth Council Entrepreneurship Working Group Meeting in March 2025?",
        "options": [
            "China",
            "Brazil",
            "India",
            "South Africa",
            "Russia"
        ],
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "question": "Marcus Stoinis, who recently announced his retirement from ODIs ahead of the Champions Trophy, represents which country in international cricket?",
        "options": [
            "England",
            "Australia",
            "South Africa",
            "New Zealand",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of NASA's new space telescope set to launch in February 2025, which aims to survey the entire sky in 102 infrared colors?",
        "options": [
            "SPHEREx",
            "James Webb Space Telescope 2.0",
            "Hubble Space Telescope 2.0",
            "Chandra-CRISP X-ray Observatory",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "SPHEREx"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country recently passed strict hate crime laws, imposing a minimum 12-month jail term for public Nazi salutes and up to six years for terror-related hate crimes?",
        "options": [
            "Canada",
            "Australia",
            "Germany",
            "United Kingdom",
            "Japan"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization launched the \"Imagine a world with more women in science\" campaign marking the 10-year anniversary of the International Day of Women and Girls in Science.?",
        "options": [
            "UNESCO",
            "UNHCR",
            "International Science Council",
            "International Union of Pure and Applied Physics",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "UNESCO"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where will the sixth edition of the India-Japan joint military exercise Dharma Guardian 2025 be held?",
        "options": [
            "Tokyo",
            "Sapporo",
            "Osaka",
            "Mount Fuji",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "China has approved the construction of a deepwater research facility that will be located at a depth of ____________ below the ocean surface in the South China Sea?",
        "options": [
            "2,000 meters",
            "2,500 meters",
            "3,000 meters",
            "3,500 meters",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "To which country did India send its first-ever sea shipment of pomegranates?",
        "options": [
            "United States",
            "Canada",
            "United Kingdom",
            "Australia",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the theme of World Radio Day 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Radio and Technology",
            "Radio and Climate Change",
            "Radio and Education",
            "Radio and Global Connectivity",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country received $5 lakh relief assistance from India for rehabilitation after a 7.4 magnitude earthquake in December 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Tonga",
            "Fiji",
            "Samoa",
            "Vanuatu",
            "Kiribati"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the Pakistani satellite launched into space by China in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "PRSC-EO1",
            "PRSS-1",
            "PakTES-1A",
            "Tianlu-1",
            "Noor-07"
        ],
        "answer": "PRSC-EO1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the title of the legislation recently passed by the US House to bar transgender athletes from women's sports at federally funded schools, defining sex by birth biology?",
        "options": [
            "Equality in Athletics Act",
            "Protection of Women and Girls in Sports Act",
            "Fair Play in Sports Act",
            "Women's Sports Equity Act",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is experiencing an outbreak of human metapneumovirus (HMPV)?",
        "options": [
            "Indonesia",
            "China",
            "Japan",
            "South Korea",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is home to the Tianshan Shengli Tunnel, the world's longest expressway tunnel?",
        "options": [
            "Mongolia",
            "Japan",
            "China",
            "South Korea",
            "Vietnam"
        ],
        "answer": "China"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did the 18th 'Suryakiran' military exercise between India and Nepal commence?",
        "options": [
            "Kathmandu",
            "Rupandehi",
            "New Delhi",
            "Bihar",
            "Tamil Nadu"
        ],
        "answer": "Rupandehi"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which countries are participating in the 4th edition of Exercise La Perouse in which INS Mumbai, an indigenously built destroyer, is also participating?",
        "options": [
            "Australia, France, India, Germany, Japan, South Korea, USA, and U.K.",
            "Australia, France, USA, U.K., India, Indonesia, Malaysia, Singapore, and Canada",
            "France, USA, U.K., Germany, Singapore, Italy, Ukraine, Moldova and Canada",
            "India, USA, Singapore, Malaysia, Thailand, Cambodia, Philippines and Australia",
            "Germany, Singapore, Italy, Ukraine"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is hosting the 1st International Pashmina Festival to promote \"Chyangra Pashmina\"?",
        "options": [
            "India",
            "Bhutan",
            "Pakistan",
            "Nepal",
            "Afghanistan"
        ],
        "answer": "Nepal"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the slogan for the UAE's 2025 \"Year of Community\" initiative announced by President Sheikh Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan?",
        "options": [
            "Together We Can",
            "United We Stand",
            "Hand in Hand",
            "Building Bridges",
            "Lets Stand"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which countries officially became full members of the Schengen Border-Free Zone on January 1, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Ukraine and Moldova",
            "Serbia and Montenegro",
            "Romania and Bulgaria",
            "Croatia and Slovenia",
            "Greece and Turkey"
        ],
        "answer": "Romania and Bulgaria"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the theme of the 15th edition of Asia's biggest aero show, Aero India 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Wings of Innovation",
            "The Sky's the Limit",
            "Advancing Atmanirbhar Aerospace for All",
            "The Runway to a Billion Opportunities",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "The Runway to a Billion Opportunities"
    },
    {
        "question": "India became an observer state in which international programme focused on intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance?",
        "options": [
            "Eurodrone",
            "Global Hawk",
            "Skyshield",
            "NATO Surveillance Programme",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Eurodrone"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nepal launched the 'Child Marriage Free Nepal' campaign with support from Indian and Nepalese organizations. Who led the 'Child Marriage Free Nepal' campaign along with child rights activists?",
        "options": [
            "K P Sharma Oli",
            "Kishor Sah Sudi",
            "Just Right for Children",
            "BASE Nepal",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Kishor Sah Sudi"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country became the 10th full member of BRICS in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Indonesia",
            "Myanmar",
            "China",
            "Finland",
            "Both 1 and 2"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Lake Turkana\" is the largest desert lake in the world, it is situated in which of the following countries of the world?",
        "options": [
            "United Arab Emirates",
            "Turkey",
            "Kenya",
            "Oman",
            "Nigeria"
        ],
        "answer": "Kenya"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country unveiled its first national autism strategy with AU$42.3 million in funding, aiming to improve inclusion and support for autistic individuals, focusing on education, employment, and diagnostic reforms?",
        "options": [
            "United Kingdom",
            "Australia",
            "Canada",
            "New Zealand",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Australia"
    }
]